Hello everyone and welcome to English pod.
My name is Marco and my name is
Catherine and today we have a very
exciting elementary lesson for you. That's
right we are going to take our clothes
to the dry cleaners. Okay so that means
we have some dirty clothes they
need to be cleaned. Let's listen to this
dialogue one time and when we come
back we'll be talking about the words and
phrases that you hear in it.
Thank God you were open. I have an
emergency. Hello Mr. Henson. What can I do
for you? I need this dress and this
suit dry cleaned ASAP. Okay I can have it
ready by the end of the week. No you don't
understand. I need this tomorrow morning.
I accidentally spilled beer all
over my wife's dress and we have a
wedding to attend tomorrow. She's
going to kill me. Okay I can have it ready
tomorrow afternoon but this suit is
also very stained. I can't guarantee we can
remove it completely. Fine.
Can you also iron and starch this shirt?
Suddenly. Great. This is our secret. If you
see my wife say nothing to her about this.
All right we're back so now there are
probably a couple of words that you didn't
understand. So why don't we look
at those now in language take away.
Language take away. Marco you already
told our listeners about one phrase to
dry clean so dry cleaned. All right so
that's when you take your clothes to a
professional who doesn't only wash them
right you don't just put water and soap on
it. They actually put some special
chemicals and use special machines to get
very hard to remove stains from it.
Exactly and so this is often what we use
when we clean coats or fancy shirts and
dresses because you don't want to clean
those yourself. You can't put those in
the washing machine. No so this is the dry
cleaner that's the name of the place
and the action what they do is they dry
clean clothes. Okay very good. All right
well I mentioned that we take them to the
dry cleaners because we want to remove
stains. Okay so a stain is a mark or some
color that does not come off does not
go away. All right so for example sometimes
you can have a wine stain. Ooh wine
stains are the worst. They're red and they
never come off or blood stain or
blood stain. Right so you can a stain is a
noun but you can also
use it as an adjective.
My shirt is stained.
Okay so it's stained.
My pants are stained and I can't
wear them again. Again that's also you
can also use it as a verb. I stained
my pants. All right so it's a verb.
It's a noun and an adjective all in one.
Easy to remember. Well there's another word
that's well related to this word. We
spilt something. Okay so I spilled wine and
it stained my shirt. Okay so to spilt
and that means that you took some liquid
and you put it on to your clothes. Or
you dropped it and it made a mess. Okay so
spill I spilled some milk. Okay spilled.
Now it's pronounced differently from
spelt right? That's right this has a spilt.
And I spilled. All right now our next
word is also a noun and a verb to iron.
To iron means to make something flat with
no lines. Okay smooth it out. So we use
an iron to iron. Exactly so it's a metal
electronic object. It gets very hot. So
you wash your shirts for example and your
shirts are wrinkled because you just
washed them. So you need to iron them.
That's right and so you smooth them out
you flatten them with this object and iron.
Okay and well usually if you take them
to the dry cleaners they will iron them
and also starch them. Okay so to starch
something means to use some powder or
chemical to make something stiff or hard.
So the the noun or the the chemical is
also called starch. Exactly so you think
of a shirt with many buttons that a man
wears to work. He has a collar around his
neck and that needs to be high and tall.
They can't be flat and wrinkled. And
so a dry cleaner will use starch to make
sure that this stands up. Okay very good.
So those are five key words for the
dialogue today. Let's
listen to the dialogue
again and we'll be back
with Fluency Builder.
Thank God you're open. I have an emergency.
Hello Mr. Henderson what can I do
for you? I need this dress and this
suit dry cleaned ASAP. Okay I can have it
ready by the end of the week. No you don't
understand. I need this tomorrow morning.
I accidentally spilled beer all
over my wife's dress and we have a
wedding to attend tomorrow. She's gonna
kill me. Okay I can have it ready tomorrow
afternoon but this suit is also very
stained. I can't guarantee we can remove it
completely. Fine. Can you also iron
and starch this shirt? Certainly. Great.
This is our secret. If you see my
wife say nothing to her about this.
All right we're back now so let's take
a look at Fluency Builder. Thank God.
Thank God. All right what is this phrase?
Thank God. Okay this is a is a phrase we
use in English to say that we're happy
about something or that we're relieved.
Okay so maybe I'm nervous that
the male isn't going to come today and
then the male comes and I say oh
thank God the male came. Yeah I'm happy.
I was I was hoping it would come. So you're
relieved. Thank God. Now is it we are
using the word their God but it doesn't
really have a kind of like a religious
connotation. Not much right. Not anymore.
No. It's usually just a phrase. Exactly.
Okay now what about this acronym ASAP
or ASAP? ASAP so as soon as possible as
an acronym so the first letter comes
from the word it means as soon as
possible very quickly right away. You always
hear that in an office setting as well.
I need those papers ASAP. I need
those reports ASAP. Exactly so you can
say it either way ASAP or ASAP and it
means immediately. Okay and he said that
he needed the suit ASAP and he said I
can have it ready by the end of the week.
Okay so that might not be fast enough
for the client for the person here who has
the stain but at the end of the week
is a very very useful phrase because it
means that maybe today's Monday or
Tuesday by Friday or Saturday we'll have
this ready for you. No because we think
of the end of the week as Friday maybe
Thursday Friday. So I can say the end
of the week or the end of the day. Exactly
the end of the month or the end of the
year. Exactly so the end of is usually the
last time so thank goodness it's the end
of the week. I'm ready for my weekend.
Very good okay so great phrases there
as well let's listen to the dialogue for
the last time. Thank God you were open.
I have an emergency. Hello Mr. Henson what
can I do for you? I need this dress and
this suit dry cleaned ASAP. Okay I can have
it ready by the end of the week. No you
don't understand. I need this tomorrow
morning. I accidentally spilled beer all
over my wife's dress and we have a wedding
to attend tomorrow. She's gonna kill me.
Okay I can have it ready tomorrow
afternoon but this suit is also very
stained. I can't guarantee we can remove it
completely. Fine can you also iron and
starch this shirt? Suddenly great this is
our secret if you see my wife
say nothing to her about this.
Alright we're back to now. Dry cleaning
ironing. Are you good at this or do you
get a lot of your clothes dry
cleaned? I'm pretty good at this actually.
I don't like to wash clothes. I get really
bored with the washing machine but I
actually really like ironing. Really? Yeah
I find it very relaxing. Really? I usually
find it very frustrating. Really why is
that? Because I can't really iron well
because I you know I start on one
side and I'm getting all the lines out and
then the other side gets wrinkled or
you know lines appear what I don't want
them to appear. It's very frustrating
for me. It is frustrating. It takes some
practice. My suggestion is to use the
the spritzer you know the in the iron
there's some water that can come out.
Like that? Well if you if you spray the
water it it makes the the lines go out
for longer. Right? Because if you iron
over that it's more permanent. I've
also seen some sprays sometimes that you
can spray your clothes with some
special chemical. That's not actually
starch but it helps remove the
wrinkles quicker. Exactly. I don't use that
I use water generally but they're
all available. Alright so that's all the
time we have for today. If you have any
questions or comments you can visit our
comment section on EnglishPod.com and we'll
see you guys there. Bye everyone. Bye!